Tom S. Gao

Full-Stack Software Developer Los Angeles, CA

SUMMARY

Hello! I'm a Full-Stack Developer with over 15 years of experience in developing Client-Server Applications, Web Applications, SOAP/RESTful Web Services, Back-End Services, Databases, CI/CD Pipelines, Test Automation, and Enterprise Integration Solutions. I possess strong fundamental knowledge in Software Design Patterns, Best Practices, and Distributed Architecture. I also love Hiking, Traveling, and Unity Game Development.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCY

Languages

C#, Golang, JavaScript, Python, PowerShell, Java, PHP, SQL, XML, HTML, CSS.

Frameworks

WebAPI SOAP/REST, WCF, IPaaS (Mule, Informatica, BizTalk), Jenkins Pipeline, Node, Express, Serverless, Puppeteer/Mocha, Selenium, Sitecore, Android Studio, Flutter SDK, .NET Core, SQL Server, MySQL, Linux, Socket.IO, Unity.

Cloud

Elastic Beanstalk, ECS, EC2, S3, Lambda, API Gateway, SQS, Kinesis, CloudFormation, RDS, Aurora. I also have experience w/ Azure and Mongo DB Atlas.

Disciplines

MVC, SOA, Microservices, REST, Parallel Threading, Async Programming, Test-Driven, Factory Pattern, Dependency-Injection, Unit Testing, Batch processes & ETL, SQL: Stored Procedures, Views, Pivot Tables, Query Optimization.

Productivity

Agile/Scrum, XP, Git, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Teams, MS Office, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Blender.

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer

Feb 2020 - Present

Cell: (619)942-4433

Email: mrtomgao@gmail.com

Website: mrtomgao.github.io/hello

Dine Brands, Glendale CA

- Developed solutions for 3rd party integrations into our Restaurant Systems. This included Customer Loyalty, 3rd Party Fulfillment, Online Ordering, Payment Gateways, Pay-At-Table, and B.I. / Marketing.
- Contributed to Design & Implementation of Enterprise Menu Management System for 3400+ Restaurants.
- Lead development on a Disaster Recovery Solution which automated Restaurant Database Backups to AWS Glacier (Multipart Upload) during non-invasive early morning hours of stores.
- Lead development on new DevOps pipeline for our Digital Products. This included the use of
 Docker containers to set up Jenkins Build & Test Agents, using Packer to create baked Machine
 Images, using CloudFormation to rapidly create Resources + Environments. Developed a
 GoLang console app which utilized the AWS SDK to automate all Sys. Admin processes
 including Blue/Green Canary deployment.
- Lead development on integration of real-time Salesforce Webhooks for Restaurant Hours & Location, for our Digital Platform's Microservices Architecture.
- Worked on IPaaS project to decouple point-to-point integrations. Use of Mule DataWeave to map Schemas. Created custom Endpoints to handle complicated orchestrations involving Restaurants and 3rd parties relaying information to one another.
- Worked on POC for use of Mocha/Puppeteer stack to handle automated browser testing for our Digital Products. (Previously it was a hybrid of Manual Testing + Selenium)
- Hand coding PowerShell & Python scripts to deploy to Windows and Linux servers.

Programmer Analyst 3, AVP

Jun 2018 - Feb 2020

City National Bank, Los Angeles CA

 Worked on solutions involving 3rd party integrations, Bill Payment, Credit Card Payment, International ACH, Client Rewards, Deposit Images, End-of-day Batch Processing, and Customer-Facing Interfaces.

- Lead development on projects end-to-end, which included defining Business Rules, Acceptance Criteria, Technical Requirements, Time Estimation, Story Grooming, Architectural Documentation, and writing Unit Tests.
- Lead Scrum Teams between 4-8 people, in collaboration with other teams to develop components of a larger cohesive system.
- Guide Jr. Developers and Off-shore Contractors. This included assisting them with their Dev Environment, Helping them kick-off their Projects, and Code Reviews.

Web Applications Developer

Nov 2016 - March 2018

Extron, Anaheim CA

- Created and helped support existing Web Applications for our Brand Website. This included Builders, Calculators, and Configuration tools which helped consumers spec & plan a purchase.
- Lead Proof of Concept efforts for a redesign of our consumer facing Home Page. This involved a framework revamp from .NET Webforms to a MVC / WebAPI decoupled architecture.

Web Developer Aug 2016 - Oct 2016

Illumina, San Diego CA

• Contract job to create a new Employee Onboarding Web App. This included Progress Tracking, Interactive Clickable-Videos, Quiz, Completion Certificate Issuance, and SSO Integration.

Applications Programmer

Nov 2008 - May 2013

Henry M. Jackson Foundation, San Diego CA

- Development and Support of an application written to provision DNA sequencing Run Analysis and Reporting for PCR, Virology, and Bacteriology.
- Developed an intelligent data collection application which detected patterns in Light Cycler readings and automatically notified Lab Researchers.
- Assisted in data collection/reporting with first discovery of H1N1 (Swine Flu) Pandemic case in USA.

Web Developer Sep 2004 - Nov 2008

San Diego County Office of Education, San Diego CA

- Developed and supported a Suite of Web-Based Online Learning Resources. This included design
 implementation of client-facing media experiences coded in ActionScript and ColdFusion.
- Developed a CRM application which tracked Login, Access, and Client License Subscriptions.

EDUCATION

Solutions Architect Associate SAA-C02

May 2021

Amazon Web Services Certification Program

Bachelor of Science Fall 2000 - Winter 2004

Computer Information Systems, School of Business Administration California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA